Guide to the Cedric N. Chatterley Photographs, 1983-2013 and undated RL.00219
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Cedric N. Chatterley photographs
1983-2013 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Chatterley, Cedric N., 1956-
RL.00219
15 Linear Feet 29 boxes
The photographs of Cedric N. Chatterley span the years 1983-2013, and were created throughout his career as a documentary photographer, beginning with his MFA thesis project on religious experience in the U.S. The photographs are primarily black-and-white prints ranging in size from 8x10 to 18x24 inches. The most prominent themes in Chatterley's work are labor, community, and religious expression. He has photographed chicken slaughterhouse workers in Maine; Cambodian immigrants in North Carolina; David "Honeyboy" Edwards and other Southern blues musicians in Mississippi and on tour; a substance abusers' rehabilitation community in Durham, N.C.; tornado survivors in South Dakota; an abandoned religious theme park in Connecticut; and sheep rancher Judith Fae "Pachy" Burns in Montana. Some of his documentary work also includes oral history interviews. There are also several recordings of interviews with Chatterley, where he speaks about his work as a documentary photographer, and a book by Barbara Lau containing his photographs of Cambodian immigrants. Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Arrangement
The collection is comprised of nine thematic series: the first is Career Retrospective, 1983-2007, with nine sub-series: Social Events, Religious Iconography, Labor, Southern Landscapes, Travel, Family, Maine Folklife, TROSA, and Downeast North Carolina. The other series are in chronological order: Holy Land, USA; MFA Thesis; Penobscot Poultry; David "Honeyboy" Edwards; Spencer, South Dakota; Triangle Residential Options for Substance Abusers (TROSA); Sheep Ranching in Montana; Other Images; and Publications and Interviews.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research. However, all reproduction requires permission of the photographer who retains the copyrights.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Original audiovisual materials are closed to patron use. Some use copies are available.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Cedric N. Chatterley Photographs were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2008, 2009, and 2014.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1956 May 6 Cedric N. Chatterley born in Massena, New York
1987 May Master of Fine Arts thesis, Ambivalent Ecstasies/Converging Energies, exhibited at the University of Southern Illinois, Carbondale
1988-1989 In collaboration with Steven Cole, conducted six interviews with Linda Lord about her work at Penobscot Poultry in Maine
1999 Publication of I Was Content and Not Content: the Story of Linda Lord and the Closing of Penobscot Poultry, authors Alicia Rouverol and Steven Cole, photographs by Chatterley (Southern Illinois Press)
2002 July Production completed of Honeyboy, a film documentary on bluesman David "Honeyboy" Edwards, with photographs contributed by Chatterley, directed by Scott L. Taradash
2003 "Each One, Teach One," exhibit featuring the Durham, N.C. program, Triangle Residential Options for Substance Abusers (TROSA), from a project conducted by Barbara Lau and Cedric Chatterley through the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University
2003-2005 From Cambodia to Greensboro: Tracing the Journeys of New North Carolinians, curated by Barbara Lau, photographs by Chatterley; organized by the Greensboro Historical Museum, Greensboro, North Carolina
2006 Began making his own large format cameras
2010 January 18-28 March Exhibit of Chatterley's portraits of "Honeyboy" Edwards and other blues musicians, 1991-1996, Rare Book, Manuscript, and Special Collections Library at Duke University, Durham, N.C., with concurrent exhibitions at the Center for Documentary Studies
2012 North Carolina at Work: Cedric Chatterley's Portraits and Landscapes of Traditional Labor, exhibit of photographs at the North Carolina Folklife Institute, Durham, N.C.
Collection Overview
The photographs of Cedric N. Chatterley span the years 1983-2013, and were created throughout his career as a documentary photographer, beginning with his Master in Fine Arts thesis project, Ambivalent Ecstasies/Converging Energies, on American religious experience. The photographs are primarily black-and-white gelatin silver prints ranging in size from 8x10 to 18x24 inches.
The most prominent themes in Chatterley's work are labor, community, and religious expression. He has photographed chicken slaughterhouse workers in Maine; Cambodian immigrants in North Carolina, a project undertaken with Barbara Lau of the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University; David "Honeyboy" Edwards and other Southern blues musicians in Mississippi and on tour; a substance abusers' rehabilitation community in Durham, N.C., also with Barbara Lau; tornado survivors in South Dakota who rebuilt their town over a period of ten years; Holy Land USA, an abandoned religious theme park in Connecticut; and a woman sheep rancher's work during lambing season in Montana. Some of the images were taken with Chatterley's hand-built cameras.
A final series consists of materials relating to Barbara Lau's book, From Cambodia to Greensboro, documenting Cambodian immigrants in North Carolina, that includes images taken by Chatterley, and a set of recorded interviews from 2008 in which Chatterley speaks about his career as a documentary photographer. The cassettes have been converted to digital files and use copies are available for access. Original recordings are closed to use.
Series are arranged in chronological order; prints are numbered and captioned by the photographer.
Acquired as part of the Archive of Documentary Arts at Duke University.
Related Material
MF 045, One Year Later: The Closing of Penobscot Poultry and the Transition of a Veteran Employee (interviews with Linda Lord, 1988-1989, and traveling exhibit materials and recordings of forums, 1989)
University of Maine, Maine Folklife Center
Amusement parks -- Pictorial works; Poultry plants -- Employees; Cambodian Americans -- Pictorial works; Popular culture -- United States -- 20th century -- Religious aspects; Migrant labor -- Montana; Poultry plants -- Pictorial works; Parks -- Waterbury (Conn.) -- Pictorial works; Mississippi -- Pictorial works; Immigrants -- North Carolina; Holy Land U.S.A.(Waterbury, Conn.) -- Pictorial works; African American musicians -- Mississippi; Mississippi -- Social life and customs; North Carolina -- Pictorial works; Photographers -- South Dakota; Slaughtering and slaughter-houses -- Maine; South Dakota -- Pictorial works; Spencer (S.D.) -- Pictorial works; Tornadoes -- South Dakota -- Pictorial works; Gelatin silver prints; Durham (N.C.) -- Pictorial works; Documentary Photography -- United States; Blues musicians -- Mississippi -- Pictorial works; Black-and-white photographs; Belfast (Me.) -- Pictorial works; Audiocassettes; Montana -- Pictorial works; Women ranchers -- Pictorial works; Drug addicts -- Rehabilitation; Waterbury (Conn.) -- Pictorial works; Drug addiction -- Treatment; United States -- Religion -- 20th century; Sheep farming -- Pictorial works; Drug addicts -- Durham (N.C.) -- Pictorial works; Sheep ranchers -- Montana -- Pictorial works; Ranching -- Montana -- Pictorial works; Sheep shearers (Persons) -- Pictorial works; Sheep ranches -- Pictorial works; Archive of Documentary Arts (Duke University); Chatterley, Cedric N., 1956- --Interviews; Burns, Judith Fae (Pachy); Chatterley, Cedric N., 1956-; Triangle Residential Options for Substance Abusers, Inc.; Penobscot Poultry; Lord, Linda, 1948-; Lau, Barbara (Barbara A.); Edwards, Honeyboy
- Career Retrospective Series, 1983-2007, 4 boxes; 127 prints
  Scope and Contents note
  Consists of nine sub-series spanning Chatterley's career as a documentary photographer: Social Events, Religious Iconography, Labor, Southern Landscapes, Travel, Family, Maine Folklife, TROSA, and Downeast North Carolina, with the bulk of the series made up of Social Events and Labor. Original captions were taken from back of prints. Subseries are arranged in a chronological sequence; the 127 prints within are in original order as received.
  - Social Events, 1983-2002, 2 folders
    Thirty-nine 11x14 inch selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting social events at various locations around the United States.
    - Female oil wrestlers and participant from the crowd. The Bermuda Triangle Bar, Reno, Nevada, 1983 Summer (Box 1)
    - Oil wrestler "Cat Woman." Reno, Nevada, 1983 Summer (Box 1)
    - Man at carnival. Elko, Nevada, 1983 Summer (Box 1)
    - Wedding party, Las Vegas, Nevada - Thanksgiving weekend, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Wedding agent, Las Vegas, Nevada (western edge), 1983 (Box 1)
    - Las Vegas, Nevada, New Year's Eve, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Mother with her children at a roller rink in Logan, Utah, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Wet T-shirt contest at the Ban Dar, Ventura, California, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Archie, dressed in service uniform, posing near photograph of his deceased wife. Hotel Logan, Logan, Utah, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Whip cream wrestling contestant conversing prior to match. Ventura County Fairgrounds, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Square dance caller. Ventura County, California, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Square dance caller. Ventura County, California, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Square dancers. Ventura County, California, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Full Gospel Church, Ventura, California, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Christmas Parade, Camarillo, California, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Boys with guns and flying kites. Lake Michigan shore, near Evanston, Illinois, 1985 Winter (Box 1)
    - St. Patrick's Day Parade - Chicago, Illinois, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Middle school spring dance - near Olmstead/Grand Chain, Illinois, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Young boxer. Houston, Texas, 1985 Summer (Box 1)
    - South Philadelphia, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Preparing for the Rose Parade. Pasadena, California, New Year's Day, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Semipro (amateur) wrestlers. National Guard Armory, Kennett, Missouri, 1986 Spring (Box 1)
    - Carnival, Mounds, Illinois, 1986 Fall (Box 1)
    - Cairo, Illinois (looking toward Commercial Street), 1986 (Box 1)
    - King Coal Festival (Local military recruiters were on hand). West Frankfort, Illinois, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Young man sitting with his brother's car parts. A.K.A. Car enthusiast. West Frankfort, Illinois, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Amateur boxing match. Murphysboro, Illinois, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Amateur boxer. Murphysboro, Illinois, 1986 (Box 1)
    - (God Loves You) Du Quoin State Fair. Du Quoin, Illinois, 1986 (Box 1)
    - KKK march, Staunton, Virginia, 1986 (Box 1)
    - Zoo, Houston, Texas, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Wedding trade show - the entrance to the Provo High School gymnasium, Provo, Utah, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Wedding trade show, Provo High School gymnasium, Provo, Utah, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Passion play by local high school students. Del Rapids, South Dakota, Good Friday, 1998. (Box 1)
    - Carson and Barnes Circus, Mitchell, South Dakota, 1998 Summer (Box 1)
    - Rodeo contestant, Mitchell, South Dakota, 1998 (Box 1)
    - College radio, Kingsville, Texas, 1999 Fall (Box 1)
    - David Grey taking a break while skating the Eastport, Maine waterfront - on the last night it was legal, 2001 Aug. (Box 1)
    - Memorial Day, 2002 (the first Memorial Day following the 9-11-01 tragedy) Fulton Ferry, looking toward Manhattan, New York City (Box 1)
  - Religious Iconography, 1983-2007, 1 folder
    Ten 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting religious imagery found across the United States.
    - Under a bridge near the entrance at Camarillo State Hospital. Camarillo, CA, 1983 (Box 1)
    - Churchyard, Moorpark, California, 1984 (Box 1)
    - Gift shop - Holy Land, U.S.A., Bedford, Virginia, 1985 Summer (Box 1)
    - Healing. Marion, Illinois, 1985 (Box 1)
    - Broken grave marker. Laredo, Texas, 1997 Summer (Box 1)
    - Passing a cross made of PVC plastic, Rt. 82. Cameron Parish, Louisiana, 1997 (Box 1)
    - Boy riding the Brooklyn Carousel, 1999 Oct. (Box 1)
    - Street preacher taking a break before starting up again. Mt. Airy, North Carolina, 2000 Oct. (Box 1)
    - Baptism. Ashe County, North Carolina, 2000 Fall (Box 1)
    - Pioneer Village at the Castle Valley Pageant. Emery County, Utah, 2007 Aug. (Box 1)
  - Labor, 1984-2004, 2 folders
    Thirty-two 11x14 selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting work at various locations around the United States.
    - Las Vegas, Nevada, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Man cleaning bricks. Cairo, Illinois, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Tretorn Etonic shoe plant - one week before closing. Belfast, Maine, 1989 Oct. (Box 2)
    - Tretorn Etonic shoe plant worker (shortly before closing completely). Belfast, Maine, 1989 Oct. (Box 2)
    - Moving machinery from Tretorn Etonic Shoe, Belfast, Maine. Closed fall, 1989. (Box 2)
    - Tretorn Etonic shoe plant (shortly before closing completely). Belfast, Maine, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Tretorn Etonic shoe plant. Belfast, Maine, 1989 (Box 2)
    - Bates Fabric Mill (operating @ 10% capacity). Lewiston, Maine, 1989 Fall and 1989, 8 prints (Box 2)
    - Oil field workers on a drilling rig. Western Kansas, 1997 Summer (Box 2)
    - Sugarcane processing plant. Jeanerette, Louisiana, 1997 Oct. (Box 2)
    - Sugarcane processing plant-furnaces in the basement. Jeanerette, Louisiana, 1997 Oct. (Box 2)
    - Stoking the furnace inside a sugarcane processing plant. Jeanerette, Louisiana, 1997 Oct. (Box 2)
    - White Woman Creek, western Kansas, 1997 Fall (Box 2)
    - Cotton weigh station, Tallulah, Louisiana, 1997. (Archivally processed, printed winter 2002) (Box 2)
    - Jimmy Cox holding the knife he used for 20 years to cut open boxes of cans. Stinson's Sardine Cannery (a few weeks after closing). Lubec, Maine, 1999 (Box 2)
    - Parking lot attendant. Salt Lake City, Utah, 2000 (Box 2)
    - Raising the largest circus tent in the world. Carson and Barnes 5 Ring Circus, Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2001 Summer (Box 2)
    - Men raising the largest circus tent in the world-Carson and Barnes Circus. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2001 Summer (Box 2)
    - Carson and Barnes Circus worker setting up for evening's performance. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2001 Summer (Box 2)
    - Carson and Barnes Circus - father and son team practicing before performance. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2001 (Box 2)
    - Road construction worker. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 2002 Oct. (Box 2)
    - Sue (far left), construction worker. Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, 2002 Oct. (Box 2)
    - Hot tar roofer, on top of Aberdeen Municipal Building. Aberdeen, South Dakota, 2002 Nov. (Box 2)
    - Marcus, working on the "Phillips to the Falls" project. Sioux Falls, South Dakota, 2004 Summer (Box 2)
    - Participant in Pachy Burn's "Jam to Lamb" event. Greenough, Montana, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Southern Landscapes, 1985-1995, 1 folder
    Six 11x14 inch selenium-toned gelatin silver prints of scenes from across the American South and Midwest.
    - $16 hotel room, Vicksburg, Mississippi, 1985 Summer (Box 3)
    - Sign shop, Louisville, Kentucky, 1986 (Box 3)
    - George. Cairo, Illinois, 1986 (Box 3)
    - Women tying tobacco, southern Virginia, 1994 (Box 3)
    - New Orleans, Louisiana, 1995 (Box 3)
    - Burnt car, New Orleans, Louisiana, 1995 (Box 3)
  - Travel, 1985-2001, 1 folder
    One folder containing 22 11x14 inch selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting Chatterley's travels in Mexico, England, Ireland, and Italy.
    - Tijuana, Mexico, Christmas Eve, 1985 (Box 3)
    - Mexicali, Mexico, New Year's Eve, 1985 (Box 3)
    - School children visiting the Open Air Museum near Iron Bridge. England, 1996 Sept. (Box 3)
    - Young man on double-decker bus, west of Liverpool, England, 1996 Sept. (Box 3)
    - Commuters on a train from Liverpool to London express, 1996 Oct. (Box 3)
    - Belfast, Northern Ireland. 1996 Oct. (Box 3)
    - John showing me the self-inflicted razor wounds on his neck. Belfast, Northern Ireland, 1996 Oct. (Box 3)
    - Young man jumping from one rock to another. Housing projects, Belfast, Northern Ireland, 1996 Oct. (Box 3)
    - Londonderry, Northern Ireland, 1996 Oct. (Box 3)
    - Dublin, Ireland, 1996 Oct. (Box 3)
    - Passing William Butler Yeats' grave, western Ireland, 1996 Oct. (Box 3)
    - Basilica of San Francesco, Assisi, Italy, 2000 Nov. (Box 3)
    - Basilica of San Francesco, Assisi, Italy, 2000 Nov. (Box 3)
    - Genoa, Italy - looking west, 2000 Nov. (Box 3)
    - Verona, Italy, 2000 Nov. (Box 3)
    - Catholic Church official in back seat of limousine. Rome, Italy, 2000 Fall (Box 3)
    - Man securing his license to "perform" for tourist. Rome, Italy, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Rome, Italy, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Dorf Tyrol, Italy, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Perugia, Italy, 2000 (Box 3)
    - Man boarding a bus in a small town in Northern Italy, 2001 Nov. (Box 3)
    - Young visitors at Riseria di San Saba, Italy's only WWII concentration camp - now a museum/memorial, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Family, 1988-2007, 1 folder
    Nine 11x14 inch selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting members of Chatterley's family, including two self-portraits.
    - Betsy. Halifax, Nova Scotia, 1988 Summer (Box 4)
    - My sister, Nancy Jane, receiving treatment for cancer (she died two weeks later). Ventura, California, 1989 Summer (Box 4)
    - Self portrait - Ebb Tide Motel. Brewer, Maine, 1991 Winter. (Box 4)
    - Boy playing on the same street corner in Salford, England that was once the site of my great, great grandfather's wheelsmith shop (Joseph Chatterley), 1996 Summer (Box 4)
    - Twins with dolls - negative found in a trash dumpster in Oklahoma City (sometime in the mid 1990s). (Box 4)
    - My father preparing for my mother's funeral, Sioux Falls, South Dakota (she would be buried in Ventura, California next to my sister, Nancy Jane), 1998 Feb. 22 Sunday. (Box 4)
    - My nephew, Sgt. Timothy Hamilton, standing among a grove of trees planted in memory of the servicemen who died in a plane accident near Greenland in 1986. Fort Campbell, Kentucky, 2004 Apr. (Box 4)
    - Self portrait. Swimming in the ocean a few hours after my father's funeral. Ventura, California, 2004 Sept. 11 (Box 4)
    - Street musician playing "Come, come ye saints" on his harmonica. Temple Square, Salt Lake City, Utah, 2007 Aug. (Box 4)
  - Maine Folklife, 1990, 1 folder
    Three 11x14 inch selenium-toned gelatin silver prints depicting basket-making in Maine.
    - Richard Sillabay searching for Brown Ash to make baskets. Aroostook County, Maine, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Joseph Tomah, basket maker. Houlton, Maine, 1990 (Box 4)
    - Joseph Tomah's kitchen table. Houlton, Maine, 1990 (Box 4)
  - TROSA, 2002, 1 folder
    One 11x14 inch selenium-toned gelatin silver print. See also the main series in this collection entitled Triangle Residence Options for Substance Abusers.
    - Man cleaning hallway at "T-North" (TROSA's building that was once a school). Durham, North Carolina, 2002 (Box 4)
  - Downeast North Carolina, 2004, 1 folder
    Five 11x14 inch selenium-toned gelatin silver prints of images taken by Chatterley during the summer of 1994 in Halifax County, North Carolina.
    - Hog kill, 4th of July weekend, Halifax County, North Carolina, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Hog killing, July 4th weekend, Halifax County, North Carolina, 2004 (Box 4)
    - Scotland Neck, North Carolina, 2004 July 4 (Box 4)
    - Ahoskie, North Carolina, 2004 Summer (Box 4)
    - Golden Corral Restaurant, Ahoskie, North Carolina, 2004 (Box 4)
- Holy Land USA Series, 1985-1986 and undated, 3 boxes; 50 prints and 1 item
  Consists of 50 8x10 inch selenium-toned gelatin silver prints and one larger undated laminated color placemat. Built in 1958, Holy Land USA was a religious roadside attraction in Waterbury, Connecticut. The images document the condition of the park, which closed in 1984 after 26 years of operation. Original captions taken from back of prints. Many of the images were printed in 2001. Prints are in original order as received.
  - Entrance at front gate. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Display at front entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Front entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Near front entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Display inside Catacombs. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Adam and Eve at the Garden of Eden (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Far end of the Garden of Eden (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Vandalized Garden of Eden (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Entrance to Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Vandalized/weathered display inside Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Display inside Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Vandalized crucifix inside the Catacombs (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT 1985 (Box 5)
  - Replica tomb (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1985 (Box 5)
  - Hillside at night. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Front gate/entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Canteen - to the left of the main gate. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - One of several pathways. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Near the top of the hill. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Detail of Mt. Transfiguration. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Display on far hillside. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Display near chapel. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Display near chapel. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Pathway to Catacombs. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Wall along the side of the Catacombs. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Display near the Catacomb entrance. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 5)
  - Display inside Catacombs. Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Sums everything up doesn't it? Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Display near the Catacombs (printed 1995). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Small tombstones, near front entrance (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - The Garden of Eden (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Vandalized display of Mary and Joseph (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Jesus says "Begone Satan." (printed 2001) Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Near the highest point of Holy Land, USA (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Statue on hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Display on far hillside (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)
  - Display by hillside, near the chapel (printed 2001). Holy Land, USA, Waterbury, CT, 1986 (Box 6)